https://www.houstontexans.com/news/website-privacy-policy

Effective: November 20, 2020
This privacy policy applies to the Houston Texans' website located at HoustonTexans.com (the "Website") and mobile application. The purpose of this privacy policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
When this privacy policy uses the term "personal information," we mean information that identifies a particular individual, such as your full name, street address or email address. When other information, such as a favorite team or player, is associated with personal information, it also becomes personal information for the purposes of this privacy policy.
Please read the information below to learn more about our data collection policies and practices.
1. Types Of Information That May Be Collected2. How Information May Be Collected3. How We Use The Information Collected4. With Whom The Information May Be Shared5. Send-to-a-Friend6. Chat Rooms, Forums, And Message Boards7. Links To Other Websites8. Security9. A Special Note For Parents Concerning Privacy10. Your Acceptance Of The Privacy Policy And Notification Of Changes To The Policy11. Correcting/Updating Personal Information12. Individuals Located in California13. Questions About This Privacy Policy
1. TYPES OF INFORMATION THAT MAY BE COLLECTED
The following are the types of information we may collect:
Information You Provide Us: In the course of using the Website, we may ask you to provide us with certain information, including contact information, such as your name, physical address, email address, or phone number; unique identifiers, such as your user ID, or similar information; and other personal information, such as age or date of birth, gender, job title, and school name and address.
Site Usage Information: We may receive and store certain types of internet usage information whenever you visit the Website, such as your click-stream data and your IP address. See "IP Addresses and Click Stream Data" section below. We also automatically collect information such as your Internet Service Provider (ISP), browser type, and operating system to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.
Email Communications: When you open emails from us, we may receive a confirmation noting you opened the email, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also may keep track of what emails we send you and what emails you may be receiving from our subsidiaries and affiliates. Additionally, we keep a record of what communications you have opted to receive or not to receive.
Mobile Application: When you download and use our mobile app, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID"). We collect your location-based information for our marketing purposes based on your current location. You may opt-out of location-based services at any time by editing the setting at the device level or by emailing us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com.
Other Sources of Information: We may receive information about you from other sources, such as our third party business partners and sponsors, and add it to the personal information we have collected about you.
2. HOW INFORMATION MAY BE COLLECTED
We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including but not limited to those described below:
Registration: You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personal information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Website may choose to offer, such as newsletters or contests. Participation in registration is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.
Newsletters and Website Emails: We offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Website, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our marketing partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Website. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. You may also cancel your free email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Website or in the newsletter or email. You can also e-mail the site at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com.
Contests or Sweepstakes: We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website that may require registration or the submission of personal information. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. Your personal information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used). We may also ask your permission to allow us to publicly post some of your information on the Website, such as on a winner's page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. To request removal of your personal information from our winner's page, contact us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on the Website and collect your information. In those cases, where we are not the operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes, we do not collect your information and we have no control over the information collected from you. Accordingly, we urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating.
Surveys or Voting: From time-to-time we may request personal information from you in conjunction with a survey or voting poll. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.
Cookies: As with many websites, our Website uses a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a unique, random number that is stored in the browser on your computer. Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Website whenever your computer is used to visit the Website. Cookies also let us know how many people visit our Website and where visitors go on the site. In addition, cookies can let us know other information, like what web browser is being used to access the Website. For registered users, cookies can make using the Website easier for you by saving information such as your passwords or preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Website, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Website are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Website. Cookies may also allow the Website to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, your browser should contain an option that allows you to disable or delete cookie data at any time. Some areas of the Website, however, may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, and tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy policy.
IP Addresses and Click-Stream Data: We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data. An IP address is a number associated with the service through which you access the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. At times, we also use IP addresses for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, for example regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personal information. Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request web pages from the Website. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Website, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising, and the like.
Social Media Widgets: Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and other Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
Transaction Information: If you conduct a financial transaction with our Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information and financial information. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e., to deliver the information, products or other services that you order, and to invoice you. For your protection, such information is collected and stored through encrypted means.
3. HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED
As applicable, the information you provide to us may be used to:
*-Contact you about the Website;
*-Contact you relating to your membership status;-Confirm or fulfill an order you have made;-Inform you of a prize you have won;-Monitor or improve the use of the Website;-Customize the advertising and content you see;-Monitor compliance with our terms and conditions of use of the Website; and-Send you promotional material or special offers on behalf of our marketing partners and/or their respective affiliates and subsidiaries and other third parties.
Mobile Applications: We may send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the mobile application.
4. WITH WHOM THE INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED
At times, we may share your personal information with others for various purposes. The following outlines the ways in which your information may be shared with others and the ways in which you may opt-out of having your information shared:
Agents: We may share your information with third parties who we employ to perform functions on our behalf to help us with our business activities. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending emails, removing repetitive information from customer lists, Website analysis, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for their own purposes, like sending you marketing offers about their products.
Co-Branding: There may be times where co-branding relationships exist between the Texans and our business partners and sponsors. Examples include sweepstakes, surveys, and sale of Texans tickets and merchandise. When there is co-branding, Texans information and branding will be displayed along with our business partner or sponsor's information and branding. Any instance within these co-branding relationships where personal information is collected is voluntary, and you may choose whether or not to participate. By sharing your personal information in these instances, you agree your personal information may be used by the Texans and our co-branding partners. If you have any questions or concerns about the disclosure of your personal information to our business partners and sponsors, please contact us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com.
Aggregate Information: We may share aggregate information, such as demographics and Website usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors or other organizations.
Other Promotional Offers: We may send offers to you on behalf of our marketing and business partners. When we do this, we do not give that partner your personal information. If you do not want to receive such offers, you may use the opt out method detailed in the email or change your preferences by logging into your account. You can also contact us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com. With your permission, we may share your information with select business partners so that they can provide you with special offers, promotional materials, and other materials that may be of interest to you. For example, you may be presented with an opportunity to have certain information shared with our third party business partners by 'opting in' when you enter a contest or sweepstakes or elect to receive marketing offers or other information, at the time your information is collected. Opting in is completely voluntary. If you have concerns about how your information is shared, please contact us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com.
Geolocation: We may share your geolocation data with third parties for the purpose of them serving you ads or marketing promotions based on your current location. If you wish to opt out of sharing your information in this manner please contact us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com.
Third-Party Ad Serving & Audience and Traffic Measurement Services: The Website may use a third party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or websites you might be interested in. Audience and Traffic Measurement Services allow us to collect de-identified traffic and behavior information from our Website by monitoring de-identified visitor activity. Although advertisers or other companies do not have access to the Website cookies, the Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser. Cookies allow third party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in. Other companies' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.
If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking Here[A1] . Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. Link to the NAI opt-out mechanism [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp
Business](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)
Transfers: In the event that all or substantially all of our assets are sold or transferred to another party, or another transaction occurs in which your personal information is one of the business assets transferred, all personal information that has been collected and saved may be one of the business assets we transfer. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information
Administrative or Legal Process: Your personal information may be transferred or disclosed to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process, law enforcement agencies and governmental requests, and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, and to protect the safety and rights of users of this Website.
5. SEND-TO-A-FRIEND
If you choose to use our referral service to send content from our site to a friend, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the referred content on our site. The Houston Texans do not store any of this information, and this information is only used for the specific purpose it was collected. If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com.
6. CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS, AND MESSAGE BOARDS
The Website may make chat rooms, forums and message boards available to its users. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post personal information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
7. LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES
You should be aware that when you are on the Website you could be directed to other websites beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Website onto a different website. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and marketing partners that may use the Website's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. If you visit a website that is linked to our Website, you should consult that website's privacy policy before providing any personal information.
8. SECURITY
This Website incorporates reasonable safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy and privacy of the personal information that we may collect, both during transmission and once received, and we have put into place reasonable precautions to protect such information from loss, misuse and alteration. Your personal information is transferred to our computers utilizing encryption software. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access. Our security policies are reviewed periodically and revised as required.
9. A SPECIAL NOTE FOR PARENTS CONCERNING PRIVACY
The Website is a general audience Website. We do not collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the Website. If we find that we have collected information from someone under the age of 13 we will delete it immediately.
10. YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY AND NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES TO THE POLICY
By using this Website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. We may amend this privacy policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on our Website and / or send an email to users who have provided an email address prior to the change becoming effective. We will assume that you have given your permission for your information to be used under the terms of the new privacy policy, if you do not respond to our email within thirty days or continue to use the Website thirty days after a notice is posted. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.
11. CORRECTING/UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION
Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If you would like to access your personal information, if your personal information changes (such as your email address or zip code), or if you no longer desire to access our Website, we will endeavor to provide a way to give access, correct, update, delete or remove the personal data you have provided to us. This can be done by emailing us at fanfeedback@houstontexans.com. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
We will retain your personal information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
12. INDIVIDUALS LOCATED IN CALIFORNIA
This section provides additional information to California residents whose personal information is processed by the NFL pursuant to California law such as the California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA"). If you are not a California resident, this section does not apply to you.
A.     "Shine the Light" Law
A California privacy law that went into effect on January 1, 2005, allows California residents to obtain specific information about a business's privacy practices if it shares information with other companies for those companies' direct marketing purposes.
As explained in this privacy policy, whenever you agree to let us collect personal information about you, we will always provide you with an option to prevent this information from being shared for non-administrative purposes with third parties. You can exercise this option at any time by following the steps outlined above.
Because the Website has a comprehensive privacy policy and provides you with details on how you may opt-in / opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes, we are not required to provide you with this information.
If you are a California resident and you would like to make such a request, please send an email to CAPrivacyRights@houstontexans.com or write to us at Houston Texans, Re: CA Privacy Rights, NRG Stadium, Two NRG Park, Houston, TX 77054, Attn: Website Privacy Policy
Third-Party Ad Serving and Audience and Traffic Measurement Services: We may use third-parties to serve advertisements on the Services. These third parties may set their own cookies or similar web technologies to collect information about users' online activities over time and across different websites. To manage your preferences you may opt out here http://optout.aboutads.info or http://optout.networkadvertising.org . The Services may feature Nielsen proprietary measurement software, which will allow users to contribute to market research, such as Nielsen TV Ratings. Nielsen believes that you should have a choice about whether to contribute to our research and insights. To opt out of Nielsen measurement, you need only to activate the "Limit Ad Tracking" (for iOS devices) or "Opt out of Ads Personalization" (for Android devices) option in your devices settings. For web, please visit: http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy to learn more about the Nielsen digital measurement products and your choices in regard to them.
B.     California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)
During the preceding 12 months, we may have collected the categories of personal information that are processed pursuant to the CCPA as set forth in Section 1 hereof. We do not, and will not without your consent, "sell" personal information for purposes of the CCPA. As set forth in this privacy policy, we disclose personal information to third parties for business purposes, including without limitation, for purposes of advertising, marketing, and other services performed on our behalf, to protect against fraud and malicious activity, and for other business purposes described in this policy. During the preceding 12 months, we may have disclosed the categories of personal information set forth in Section 1 for such business purposes. In addition, your information may be accessible to third parties with whom you interact or direct us to share your information through our services. With your prior express consent, we may disclose contact information to certain sponsors and/or advertisers as part of sweepstakes, contests, promotions, or other initiatives.
The CCPA allows California residents to request that a business that collects consumers' personal information give consumers access, upon a verifiable consumer request, in a portable and (if technically feasible) readily usable form, to the specific pieces and categories of personal information that the business has collected about the consumer, the categories of sources for that information, the business or commercial purposes for collecting the information, and the categories of third parties with which the information was shared. California residents also have the right to submit a request for deletion of personal information under certain circumstances, although there may be legal or other reasons that we must retain your information consistent with California law. If you choose to exercise your CCPA rights, we will not charge you different prices or provide different quality of services unless those differences are related to your personal information or otherwise permitted by law. Please submit your request by either (i) sending an email to CADataRequest@houstontexans.com or (ii) calling 866-468-3926 (toll-free). Please note that your request will not be processed until your identity is confirmed.
Once we receive your request, we may verify it by requesting information sufficient to confirm your identity. If you would like to use an authorized agent registered with the California Secretary of State to exercise your rights, we may request evidence that you have provided such agent with power of attorney or that the agent otherwise has valid written authority to submit requests to exercise rights on your behalf. We reserve the right to deny requests in certain circumstances, such as where we have a reasonable belief that the request is fraudulent or where your identity cannot be confirmed.
13. QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the privacy practices of this Website, contact fanfeedback@houstontexans.com.
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to:
Houston TexansAttn: Website Privacy PolicyNRG StadiumTwo NRG ParkHouston, TX 77054
[A1]Updated hyperlink to http://optout.aboutads.info
Advertising
Big left arrow icon
Big right arrow icon
Close icon
Copy Url
Three dots icon
Down arrow icon
InstagramTwitterFacebookSnapchatShop IconProfile Overlay
AvatarAddAirplayArrow LeftArrow RightArrow UpArrow DownAudioBack 5sBack 10sBack 30sCalendarChartCheckDownLeftRightUpChromecast OffChromecast OnCloseClosed CaptionsBench OffBench OnBroad OffBroad OnVertical OffVertical OnCommentDockDoneDownloadDraftFantasyFilterForward 5sForward 10sForward 30sFull Screen OffFull Screen OnGamepassGamesInsightsKeyLeaveLiveCombineDraftFantasyMenu GamesMenu NetworkMenu NewsMenu PlayoffsMenu Pro BowlMenu ShopMenu StandingsMenu StatsMenu Super BowlMenu TeamsMenu TicketsMenuMore HorizontalMore VerticalMy LocationNetworkNewsPauseplayMultiple PlayersSingle PlayerPlaylistPlayoffsPro BowlPurgeRefreshRemoveReplaySearchSettingsShare AndroidShare Copy URLShare EmailShare FacebookShare InstagramShare iOSShare SnapchatShare TwitterSkip NextSkip PreviousStandingsStarStatsSwapTeamsTicketsVideoVisibility OffVisibility OnVolume HiVolume LowVolume MediumVolume MuteWarningWebsite
Caret downCaret upAt
The browser you are using is no longer supported on this site. It is highly recommended that you use the latest versions of a supported browser in order to receive an optimal viewing experience. The following browsers are supported: Chrome, Edge (v80 and later), Firefox and Safari.
Got it!
